[Music]
welcome to this Buy Central lunch event
related to 2024 release Wave
2 we will introduce you uh about
multiple V8 number for customers and I
will do it together with my colleague
Arthur Vel let's see what we will talk
about today we will make first short
introduction and this introduction with
a flowchart how system is going with the
business process and then arto will show
you full demo from setup and how it work
in a practice with documents on the end
we will close this session with a a
small talk about architecture just to
understand how it work in a
background
first uh why do we need this feature at
all um this is very important this is a
legal requirement when companies operate
in different countries across the
European Union uh they need to have
different V number in each of count even
if this is the same company and now this
is not only for European Union it can be
applicable in other countries as well
but this is the the most common case in
European union and now it can be applied
not only to customers it can be applied
for all entities for customers for our
vendors for our company as well but uh
we had to start from somewhere so we
couldn't deliver everything in one hit
it was uh big changes in V uh system so
we decided to start with the customers
and we decided to start with customers
because based on our research it was the
most painful uh part related with
multiple vat numbers in a bus Central so
what we did we just added alternative V
number and additionally you can add
business posting groups so how does it
work uh first let's look in a setup and
let's imagine perfect scenario you
configure everything Advance what does
it mean uh you have
um alternative V registration table so
you can pass to this table add all your
customers and Define all uh countries
they are working with uh you can
configure one vat per country you cannot
have more countries for the same
customers because only one one customer
can have only one V number in specific
uh country and what you need to add
there you need to you must add vat
registration number and you can
optionally add vat business posting
group and General business posting group
this is perfect scenario so you have
everything configured in advance but
this is not something what we can
imagine it will work all the time this
is much more realistic scenario we have
customers we configure for some of them
alternative uh V registration but not
for all all cases and then you got a
phone call your customer ordered
something and said okay now I want to
add new ship to address in different
country and what you need to do you need
to open ship to others for this customer
busy Central once when you uh create
this new ship to address you will
probably have um different probably if
you have different uh country code you
need to configure but if not business as
usual this is just additional ship to
adds but if country uh code is different
system will first check if I already
have configur alternative V number for
this country related with this ship to
address if yes again nothing will be
changed that's normal but if you didn't
have in this moment you will be notified
you will get small notification on your
uh card where you will be notified that
you need to create you should be
actually uh create um uh you should
create new alternative v um registration
so you can decide if you
want uh because maybe by your rules this
is not necessary but if yes you just
need to say yes to confirm and syst will
open alternative V registration where
you can again enter everything what I
previously explain V registration number
and posting groups now let's explain how
it works in the practice when you work
with documents we will start with sales
documents we talking about customers and
when I say sales documents I mean on
sales invoice sales order um uh sales
credit memo so all sales documents and
now you have different ship to address
you can choose an alternative uh
shipping addresses different address or
eventually if you do not record all
these uh addresses you can choose custom
address and type manually your uh ship
to address for the sales document then
what system will do system will again
check if ship to address is in different
country if no business is usual nothing
will be changed existing V number and
posting groups will be kept so nothing
will be changed but if your shift to
address never mind if this is from
alternative or custom address is
different system will use new
new uh vat number from your
configuration uh the same for posting
groups if you have configured posting
groups but if you didn't configure you
will still get notification you do not
have uh vat uh registration for this
country so you can still create um new
configuration for uh alternative V
numbers there but now let's imagine you
have everything configured you will be
offered with a new uh V8 number and
eventually posting groups and now you
need to choose do want to accept or not
in some because some reasons you do not
want to accept so if no again business
is usual nothing will be changed you can
continue to work with document as a for
many years ago but if you want to accept
this change you just need to confirm and
system will apply new uh V number to
your document and eventually posting
groups if you have uh configured there
what does it mean uh you will get V
business posting group General business
posting group exists vat registration
number as well but you will get vat
country region code this is New Field
and you will get all of them different
based on your configuration and now what
is additionally important uh V
registration number and V country region
code will be applied when you post in V
entry so after that you can easily um
filter your V entries and you can find
uh which country you want to use for
your V statements and
returns uh just to see how it look like
before we go with the demo uh this is
how alternative customer V registration
page exist and how it look like so once
you are there you as I said you must
enter V registration number and there is
V uh number validation of course so if
you in this example if you have Danish V
number it must uh use uh validation for
Denmark and optionally you can add
generality posting group and V posting
group that's it so now we will move to
demo and Arthur will Jo will join us and
show how it
works thank you Alexander for
introduction uh let me start with the
setup in the business Central I'm in the
customer cards and there are two ways to
set up the alternative feature
registration for the first one I'm going
to open the ship to addresses from the
customer card and I'm going to create a
new ship to
address uh as you can see the country
region code is now taken from the C
customer card uh I want to change this
and when I do this uh you can notice the
notification uh that ass says that the
country of the address is different from
the customer and there will be a
suggestion to add an alternative
customer uh VT
registration uh I have two options here
add and don't show if I click add um a
new setup will be added it will be
prepopulated with the customer number
and VT count region number taken from
the ship to add address so all I need to
do is to follow up with the remaining
fields for the VT registration number I
want to intentionally uh specify the
wrong V intention number to show you
that the VT registration number format
check is working as you can see it says
that uh the format is not correct uh so
I want to choose the right V
registration number uh and I also want
to specify the general and VT business
group when I specify the general
business group you you can see that VT
business group is taken from the default
VT business group on the general
business one in the same way like it
works for the customer uh and that is it
for the setup from this ship to
address uh now when I uh change the
country region code to the other one for
example um I'm going to see the very
same the very same
notification now the other way of doing
this let me get back to the customer
card next to the ship to address a
section there is a new one that is
called alternative F registration and
the very same page will be open when we
already have a setup now I want to make
a setup for
Belgium uh I'm going to add the V
registration number and I want to
intentionally keep those two Fields
blank uh they're optional and it is fine
to not uh to not specify them that is
the second way of setting up the
feature uh now let's create uh now let
me get back to the sales orders I
already created some for the sake of
times uh for this customer and for this
sales order I'm going to use the
alternative Fe registration number
multiple ways uh I'm going to scroll
down to the shipping and baing and in
the ship to field uh there is an option
that's called alternative shipping
address and when I choose this I have a
list of ship to addresses uh I want to
choose the one I've just created and
when I do this uh I can see the
confirmation dialog page uh and I need
to explain this this confirmation doog
page concept uh since the VT area is
very sensitive one and it can affect
posting uh we thought that is a good
idea to show the users the confirmation
doll page so they can understand all the
consequences of uh choosing ship to ship
to address field in this confirmation
doll page user can see that by choosing
this ship to address uh the value of the
registration number will be changed from
the document one which is gbn 1111 to
the alternative one from the setup and
then there are two options uh it is
possible to confirm or to cancel and
when I click okay if I want to confirm
this uh we you can notice on the one top
on top the invoice details tab you can
notice that the VT VT country region
code and VT registration number has
changed so now we have uh and now I have
Belgium and now I have the VT
registration number from the setup uh as
well you can also notice that all the VT
related fields are now combined under
one tab invoice details uh so you do no
need to move uh through different uh
tabs to find the right field that is the
first option how you can do this through
the ship to address uh let me get back
to the default one and I want to pay
your attention to the following message
when we change back default ship to
address the values are now taken from
the customer card and this is message to
notify the user that the values are
taken from the customer cir when I click
okay now you can see that in VT country
region code and VT registration number
we have the Valu from the customer
card uh now the second way uh if I don't
have the ship to address I can choose
the custom
address and below I have the counter
region so what I can do here I can
choose the country region uh code that
will be associated with the alternative
um VT registration setup now you can see
the very same confirmation doll page
here you have we have more Fields
because except the V registration number
we also specified General business group
and VT business group um I also would
like to highlight the option don't show
again uh probably at some point user is
going to decide that uh there is no need
to show this confirmation dialog page
and if they click don't show again and
click okay uh whenever user going to
make all the same changes there will be
no information do page uh if I want to
bring this uh page uh back I need to go
to the my notification setup and in the
very same way like it works for
notification even though it's the page
we need to search for the alternative
and we can enable uh the confirm
alternative customer VT Reg ation setup
and now we have this page back again now
when uh all the data is here you can
post the sales order and all the values
will end up in the VT entries uh and now
when all the values are there you can
start working on reporting and there are
two more um two more things that we
implemented like a side functionality to
this one um the first one is in the VT
return uh when you create your two turn
and you click the suggest lines now
there is a new field that is called cter
region filter and you can specify one
country multiple countries exclusion
filter uh and this this uh filter will
be applied to the country region code uh
in the VT entries now the very
same the very same field um is
implemented into in the calculate and
post VT settlement when I run this one
and if I show more in the bottom you can
see the same filter that is called
country region filter and it works in
the very same way it will be applied to
the VT entries uh uh that will be filter
for the report uh and that is it with
the presentation in the business Central
now I want to talk about the
architecture review now for the
architecture review um I have created
this diagram it is a bit complex uh let
me explain how you need to read it um
from the very end of this diagram there
is consumer this is our sales model uh
and we invented the alternative feat
registration on top of it for this Sal
sales model we have the alternative fat
registration feature uh that has three
parts the first part uh that you can see
on the left side of the diagram the ship
to address the second one setup
consistency and the third one is
document the first one ship to address
uh this is all the logic that we have on
the ship to address page so when I
created a new ship to address and you
have seen the notification on this page
this is controlled by this part of
functionality and for this part part of
functionality we have the interface that
is called ship to alternate customer VT
registration and there is the method uh
that you can Implement in your own way
that is called handle country change and
ship to address so if you feel that uh
you need another implementation other
than the default one you can do that
with this interface and with this method
the second setup consistency it is um
connected both to ship to address table
and to the customer table um here the
idea is that uh the setup needs to be
consistent in the way that uh the
alternative V customer V registration
need to be only for countries other than
than the customer one uh and here we
also have the interface uh that is
called alternative customer VT
registration consist uh and it has two
methods one for the customer uh to to
check the ship address and other one to
check the customer
consistency uh if you feel that you need
other implementation for this one uh you
have the interface for that uh and the
last one the most important I guess for
the document uh this is everything that
is happening in the sales header table
here we have the interface alternative
customer VT registration Doc and several
methods when we initialize the record
when they copy values from the customer
uh on the ship to address change on the
VT country region change on the build to
customer change basically all the
scenarios that you can imagine uh in the
sales document if you want to change
this logic it is possible to do with
this interface so as you can see um the
whole feature is highly highly
extensible um and if you want to change
any part of it you can do that with your
uh interface implementation
okay thank you Arthur and we are on the
end of our session uh as a call to
action it will be try test D
functionality this is available in a
public preview and it will be available
for 25.0 version so it will be
immediately in our major and try uh we
think that we improve a lot of things in
in a V we start a few waves ago so we
introduced few more uh functionalities
about V8 previous you can find these
videos on YouTube channel but this one
is something new and we will continue
with uh upgrading functionalities in V
thank you for watching this session and
please try it